DHR&Hakugetsu Sub
翻譯：モビイ•ディック CRF 因果律 果妹子  後期：沙夏、KoU
Furuya!
降谷君！
Let's take this chance...
この際だ
...to make things clear to him, why don't we?
白黒つけようじゃないか
なあ　降谷よ
Right, Furuya?
Nemurenai yoru ni kiita monogatari ga
What if the story I heard that sleepless night
esoragoto da to shitara
was all just an impossible dream?
Eien wo shiru yori kairaku wo motomete
What if I pursue pleasure, and lament the moment
ima wo kuyande shimau no wa
instead of learning about the eternities
kokoro no fukaku ni sumitsuita kage kara
so that I can escape from the shadows
nigeru tame da to shitara
that dwell deep within my heart?
Sore demo atashi wa atashi wa ai shite irareru nara
But even so, as long as I, as long as I can still keep loving
Hanbun ni wareta taiyou ga asa wo tsurete kite
The sun split in half brings with it the morning
yami ni nareta shinkei wo jiwari shigeki suru
gradually stimulating my nerves, so used to the darkness
Okiwasureta ano ai wa aete sono mama de
I'll dare to leave the love that I'd misplaced as it is
Shinario no kieta monogatari wa
A story whose plot has been erased,
jiyuu ni jiyuu ni kaji wo totte
freely, freely, takes the helm,
motto takaku e maiagatte
soaring ever higher
"Strong... Feelings..."
Green is a healing color.
グリーンは
ヒーリングカラー
Master Furuya,
I'm so glad you've come here.
降谷様
ようこそ　お越しくださいました
Here is your welcome drink.
ウエルカムドリンクでございます
ハア～　ちょうど喉渇いてたんすよ
And just as I was getting thirsty, too!
…て　そういうシチュじゃねえよ！
But this isn't the time or place!
Well then, at your leisure.
それでは　ごゆっくり
Hey, untie me! Hey!
ほどけよ　おい！
おい！
おい　ちょっと…
Hey, come on...!
マジかよ
Is this for real?
Come on, stop screwing around!
This is full-blown kidnapping!
コラ　ふざけんな～
これは立派な誘拐だぞ！
It's illegal imprisonment!
Are you listening?! Untie me!
拉致監禁だ　聞いてんのか！
ほどけっつのッ
背中がかゆくなったらどうすんだ
What am I supposed to do when my back itches?!
Oh, it's starting to itch!
It's starting to itch! Itchy! Itchy!
ああ～　かゆくなってきた
かゆい　かゆい～
All right, you've come back.
よ～し　戻ってきたか
うるさいわね
Keep it down, will you?
Your voice is carrying down the hallway.
廊下の外まで響いてきたわよ
あんた誰だ？
Who are you?
人の家に来ておいて
That's pretty impudent backtalk,
after you come into my home.
随分ぶしつけな物言いね
I'm not here because I want to be.
好きで来たわけじゃねえよ
So it appears.
そのようね
I am Sanka Dan'ichiro's wife, Sanka Aria.
私は散華団一郎の妻
散華亞里亞よ
Oh, then you're Rea's...
じゃあ　礼弥の…
あなたが　降谷千紘君？
You must be Furuya Chihiro.
You're the one looking after Rea.
礼弥がお世話になってるわね
Well, I wouldn't go as far as
"looking after" her...
いや　世話ってほどのことは
So, how far have you gotten with her?
で　あの子とは
どこまで進んでいるの？
まだ接吻程度？
Are you still just kissing?
No, not her. As repressed
as she's been up to now,
いえ　あの子
今まで抑圧されてた分
I'll bet she's positively
insatiable, isn't she?
みだらに
発情しまくってんのかしら
W-What are you talking about?!
Rea isn't at all...
何言ってんだ　礼弥がそんな…
Oh, no? Then...
あら？　じゃあ
...you and her haven't yet...
あなた　まだ　あの子と一度も
ああ　そうよね
Ah, I suppose not.
After all, she's a "monster," huh?
なんせ　相手はバケモノだものね
And after all, being a zombie,
her body must be slowly decaying,
あれでしょ？　ゾンビってことは
だんだん体が腐って
and she must be releasing
a pretty foul stink, huh?
悪臭を放つようになるんでしょ？
肌も　どんどん汚らしくなって
Her skin must be quickly growing nasty, too.
自分が産んだ娘を
よく　そんなふうに言えるな
I'm surprised you can talk
about the girl you bore like that.
産んだ　私が？
Bore? Me?
No. I've never had any children.
いいえ　私は出産なんて
一度もしたことないわ
Huh? What do you mean?
どういうことだよ
Then, you're...
じゃあ　あんた…
I am Dan'ichiro's second wife.
私は　団一郎さんの二番目の妻
あッ…
そう
Yes. She was the child of his former wife.
あの子は　前妻との間にできた子
She is absolutely no blood relation to me.
私とは　まったく
血のつながりなんてないのよ
Rea never said anything about that.
礼弥は
そんなこと言ってなかったぞ
当然よ
Of course not.
After all, this is the greatest
shame of the Sanka family.
このことは
散華家最大のタブーですもの
知ってる者は　ごく一部よ
There are only a handful of people who know.
ついでだから話してあげる
And as long as I'm telling tales,
I used to be one of the Sanka household maids.
私は元々
この散華家のメイドだったのよ
But don't get the idea
that I am of humble origins.
だからって　下賤の身だったなんて
勘違いしないで
礼弥が生まれる以前
Before Rea was born, all of the
maids that served in this mansion
この屋敷に勤めるメイド達は皆
were also potential marriage candidates,
散華家の跡取り息子に用意された
prepared for the heirs to the Sanka family.
花嫁候補でもあったのよ
From bloodline, to education,
to cultural grounding,
家柄　教育　素養に至るまで
only those who could pass each category
あらゆる項目を
パスした者のみしか
were allowed to work in this mansion.
この屋敷で働くことは
許されなかった
ここに　あの子の写真が
飾られることはなさそうね
It doesn't appear that her photos
decorate the walls here, do they?
So as of now, let me display my picture.
だから　これからは
私の写真を飾りましょう
団一郎さんが
幼い頃から
From the time that Dan'ichiro was little,
many maids tried to
pander to him,
多くのメイド達が　散華一族の
仲間入りをするために
so that they could join the Sanka family.
彼の歓心を買おうとしていたわ
でも　団一郎さんは誰に対しても
But Dan'ichiro never showed
any sign of attraction to any of them.
まったく　なびく様子がなかった
私がメイドとして
ここに来たのは
I came here as a maid when
Dan'ichiro was a graduate student.
団一郎さんが大学院生のとき
After you worked so hard
to be a Sanka family maid,
頑張って散華家のメイドに
なれたのに残念ね
it's such a shame. The next family
head has no interest in women.
次期当主は　女に興味がないわ
あなたも　ここで飼い殺しね
You get to languish here, too.
Perhaps it's not women he has no interest in.
女に興味がないわけじゃ
ないんじゃないの？
Maybe he's just not interested
in the rest of you.
あなた達に興味がないだけで
I was sure of myself.
私には
自信があったわ
Up until then, I had
never met a man I couldn't win.
それまで私に　落とせない男は
いなかったから
Come in.
入りなさい
How did you know I wanted coffee?
なぜ　コーヒーだと分かった？
I figured you would
be done with yours by now.
そろそろ飲み終わる頃かと
I also brought a lap blanket.
ひざ掛けも
お持ちいたしました
名前は？
What's your name?
亞里亞と申します
My name is Aria.
Little by little, I came to
be called to Dan'ichiro's side.
私は徐々に
団一郎さんのそばに
呼ばれるようになった
But ultimately, Dan'ichiro was
not swayed by me, either.
でも結局　団一郎さんは
私にもなびかなかった
Master Dan'ichiro, good morning.
団一郎様　おはようございます
Yeah.
Little by little, I came to believe
徐々に私も
that Dan'ichiro was not
interested in women, myself.
団一郎さんは　女に興味が
ないのだろうと思うようになった
But then, the situation was turned on its ear.
でも　そんな状況が
一変したの
That day, in the name of social welfare,
その日は
社会福祉の一環として
those who were disadvantaged or institutionalized
障害のある人や　施設の人々を
散華家へ招き入れ
were invited to the Sanka home,
and a fencing tournament was held.
フェンシングの大会が催されたの
Naturally, Dan'ichiro was one of the contestants.
もちろん　選手の中には
団一郎さんもいて…
Wow! Master Dan'ichiro is the winner!
団一郎様の優勝よ！
Master Dan'ichiro, that was fantastic!
団一郎様　素敵だわ
C'était un bon jeu.
["That was a good match."]
Why don't you fight me like you mean it?!
なぜ　真剣勝負をしてくれない
私が負けるとでも思ったのか！
Did you think I would lose?!
The Sanka family is a major contributor
散華家は
国際フェンシング協会に
to an international fencing society.
ばく大な献金をしている
いわば最大のスポンサー
In fact, they are the primary sponsors.
It had become a foregone
conclusion that Dan'ichiro
毎年催される大会で
団一郎さんが勝つことは
決まり事になっていたの
would be the winner of the
tournament held every year.
Dan'ichiro could not read between the lines,
団一郎さんは
空気の読めないお人だから
so this custom did not appear to agree with him.
そういった通例が
お好きじゃなかったみたい
When the tournament was over,
and they were seeing the guests out,
そんな大会が終了し
来場者を見送るときのこと
this young lady spoke to Dan'ichiro.
あの娘が
団一郎さんに声をかけたのよ
Um...
あの…
Here.
これ
Y-Yeah...
I know you were probably
disappointed by your match,
試合のことで
不満があったのでしょうけど
but if you treat your things poorly,
God will let you have it.
ものを粗末にしたら
神様に叱られますよ
Even if today's matches
may not have been for real,
たとえ　今日の試合が
偽りだったとしても
as long as your practice and
effort up to now have been genuine,
あなたの　これまでの練習や
努力が本物だったら
so much the better.
なおさらです
Several days later...
その数日後
Dan'ichiro proposed to that 15-year-old girl.
団一郎さんは
その１５歳の小娘に
プロポーズをしたの
It was the most shocking
event in Sanka family history.
散華家
始まって以来の珍事よ
He pushed those of us
with proper social standing aside,
家柄正しき私達を差し置いて
and chose some frail girl, whom
we had never heard of, to be his wife.
どこの馬の骨とも分からない
虚弱な娘を妻に選ぶなんて
And that was Rea's real mother.
それが　礼弥の本当の母親
Naturally, their marriage...
当然　そんな結婚
...was fiercely opposed
by the rest of the Sanka family.
散華一族全員から
猛反対を受けたわ
But Dan'ichiro would not be
daunted by anyone's opposition.
でも　団一郎さんは
誰の反対にも屈しなかった
Her social status is an issue?
家柄が問題だと？
Of course it is! We don't
know anything about this girl!
あたりまえだろ
どこの馬の骨とも分からん娘
In that case, I will renounce my heirship.
ならば　私は家督を捨てます
By doing so, nothing will
prevent this marriage.
そうすれば
結婚に何の障害もない
What are you saying, Dan'ichiro?
何を言ってるんだ　団一郎
Don't be ridiculous!
バカなことを
言うんじゃない
Are you saying you would abandon
the Sanka family over that bimbo?!
あんな娘のために
散華家を捨てるというのか！
"That bimbo"?
あんな娘？
Please, watch your mouth.
She is to be my wife.
口を慎んでください
私の妻になる人です
As I am forsaking the Sanka
family, and becoming a stranger,
私が散華家を捨てて
他人となるなら
I expect you to mind
your manners even more.
なおさら　わきまえてもらおう
I will not tolerate anyone
speaking out of turn about my wife!
我が妻のことを
他人に　とやかく言われるのは
腹に据えかねる！
After Dan'ichiro had
silenced all of the relatives,
親戚一同を黙らせた
団一郎さんは
he married the girl.
あの女と結婚した
But the girl passed
away soon after Rea was born.
でも　礼弥を産むと
すぐに　あの女は死んでしまったわ
Dan'ichiro's depression
at the time was something awful.
あのときの
団一郎さんの落ち込みようは
ひどかったわ
Bad enough that he might
have died unless something was done.
そのまま死んでしまうのでは
ないかというぐらい
I worked desperately to bear him up,
それを私が
必死で支えて
and little by little, he recovered.
少しずつ立ち直ったのよ
And then, I finally obtained Dan'ichiro.
そして
私は　団一郎さんを手に入れた
But a year went by,
and then two, after we were married,
だけど　結婚して
一年　二年と過ぎていっても
and Dan'ichiro never
once looked on me as his wife.
団一郎さんが
私を妻として見てくれることは
一度もなかった
How do you mean by that?
それって　どういう…
You're so dim.
I mean he never made love to me.
にぶいわね
抱いてくれなかったってことよ
Dan'ichiro just thought
that the girl needed a mother.
団一郎さんは　あの子に
母親が必要だと思っただけなのよ
But in fact, she didn't
actually even need one.
しかも　実際は
母親すら必要なかった
There was nothing for me to do.
私がやることなんて　なかったもの
I would always just watch
the two of them from a distance.
私は
いつも離れたところから
二人を見ているだけで
I was never made to
feel like I was a part of the family.
家族としての絆を
感じさせてもらえなかった
What is it?
どうした
Why don't we do some traveling sometime?
たまには
旅行とか行ってみない？
If you think about it,
you and I never even had a honeymoon.
よく考えたら
新婚旅行にも行ってないのよ
私達
You're right.
そうだな
Maybe it is about time that
Rea experienced the outside world.
礼弥も　そろそろ外の世界を
体験していったほうが
いいかもしれん
We're taking Rea with us?
礼弥を連れていくの？
What are you talking about?
何を言っている
Despite it all, I believed
that Dan'ichiro chose me
それでも　私は
団一郎さんが
私を後妻に選んでくれたことに
as his second wife out of love.
愛情があったと信じていた
Mother!
お母様
Come take a picture with me,
together with Father!
お父様と一緒に写真撮ろう
All right.
いいわよ
I believed that the
love Dan'ichiro had for her
私は　団一郎さんの
あの子への愛情は
was the love one
would have for a daughter.
娘へのものだと信じていた
However...
でも…
I came because you asked me to come
here, but why exactly am I here?
ついてこいって言うから
来たけど
何なのよ　いったい
What are you doing?
何をしてるの？
I think that you should
resign yourself, Madam Aria.
亞里亞様に
諦めていただこうと思いまして
I would like you to give up
団一郎様に
愛情を求められることを
seeking for Master
Dan'ichiro's affections.
諦めていただきたいのです
What are you talking...
何を言って…
I must ask that you not raise your voice.
大きな声を立てませぬよう
お願いいたします
Now, this is how I'm posing you.
Point your feet like this.
さあ
ポーズはこうだよ
足をこう上げて
Right.
はい
You will now resign yourself, yes?
諦めていただけますね？
As it turns out,
Dan'ichiro continued to dote on her,
結局　団一郎さんは
あの子を溺愛し続けて
chasing after the spirit of
that woman in her all this time!
ずっと
あの女の面影を追っていたのよ
ふん　あの子が私の娘ですって？
That girl, my daughter, you say?
Don't suggest anything so repugnant.
気持ち悪いこと言わないでよ
It looks like her old man
礼弥が追い込まれていったのは
wasn't the only reason why
Rea was feeling so boxed in.
あの親父のせいだけじゃなかった
みたいだな
ふん
Say, Furuya, don't you
think I'm a tragic woman?
ねえ　降谷君
私って　悲しい女だと思わない？
Won't you comfort me,
with your own body?
あなたの体で
私を慰めてくれない？
There, you see? You can't enjoy
this kind of warmth from a zombie.
ねえ　ほら
ゾンビじゃ味わえない
温かみでしょ？
Sorry about that.
I'm only interested in zombie girls.
悪いっすね
おれ　ゾンビっ娘にしか
興味ないから
It's always about that girl!
みんな　あの子ばっかり！
Why?! Why won't anyone
pay any attention to me?!
なんで　なんで
私のこと見てくれないのよ～！
Oh, kitty-cat, are you here to comfort me?
あッ　子猫ちゃん
あなた　私のこと慰めてくれるの？
Just for me?
こんな私のこと
Ah, you darling, sweet little guy...
いとおしい
優しい子
He's a zombie, too...
それもゾンビですけど
いやッ！
Somebody, come chase these
two rude brutes out of the mansion!
誰か　この無礼者二匹を
屋敷から
追い出してしまいなさい！
いや　俺も出ていっていいんなら
むしろ出ていきたいんだけど
You know, if I'm free to
leave here, I'd be happy to go.
I'm afraid we can't have that.
そういうわけには
まいりません
Master Dan'ichiro is expecting you.
団一郎様が　お呼びです
Listen, as I told you before,
this is clearly kidnapping.
あのさ　さっきも言ったけど
これって　明らかな拉致なわけだよ
I don't care if Master Dan'ichiro
is the head of the Sanka family,
団一郎様が散華家の当主だか
何だか知んないけど
I don't think he has the
right to put me through this.
俺をこんな目にあわす権利は
ないと思うんだけど
And with that in mind, could you
at least release me from this thing?
というわけで　せめて
これ　ほどいてくれねえか？
No, I can't.
できません
Yeah, right.
だよな
いいじゃない
うらやましいわ
Lucky you. I'm jealous.
You'll get to spend some time with him.
あの人に
相手にしてもらえるなんて
He's never once
spent any real time with me, yet.
私なんて　まだ一度も
ちゃんと相手にしてもらったこと
なんてない
Uh, excuse me, could you turn
the air conditioner on any stronger?
あッ　あの　冷房を
もっと強くしてもらえますか？
All right.
あいよ
Is it really that warm out today?
今日　そんなに暑かったっけ？
I'm sure that's it.
Those men earlier were sent by Father.
きっと　そうだわ
さっきの人達は
父が仕向けた手下
Furuya is in trouble!
降谷君が危ない
Excuse me, but can you go any faster?
すいません
もっと急いでもらえますか？
All right.
はいよ
Does this girl even have any money?
この子　お金持ってるのかな
Please wait here.
こちらで　お待ちください
What is this? I thought
Master Dan'ichiro was expecting me.
何だよ
団一郎様がお呼びじゃねえのかよ
Just wait here, please.
ですから　お待ちください
Hey!
おい！
チェッ
I took all of these photos.
すべて　私が撮ったものだ
There he is.
出たな
At every time, at every
instant that I snapped one,
いつ　いかなる瞬間を切り取っても
Rea has been beautiful.
礼弥は美しい
After all, she is the very
embodiment of "innocence,"
なぜなら　彼女は
はかなさと美しさで織りなされた
純真そのものだからだ
woven from evanescence and beauty.
I have been preserving Rea's "innocence."
私は　礼弥の純真を守り続けてきた
I am grateful to you.
私は　君に感謝しているのだ
Huh?
By losing Rea,
一度　礼弥を失ったことで
I once again strongly
feel my love for her within me.
改めて　私の中の
礼弥愛を
強く感じることができたのだ
I now want to preserve her even more!
より　守りたいと思えたのだ
Thank you.
ありがとう
But you will pay...
だが　許さん
降谷千紘
...Furuya Chihiro...!
Hitotsu dake kanau no nara
If I had just one wish
kimi no te no naka yureru chiisa na hana de itai
I would want to be a small flower, trembling in your hands
Hajimete miru mabushii kono sekai ga
Even if I become separated from you,
kimi to moshi hagureta to shite mo kitto
in this bright world I'm seeing for the first time,
mitsukedashite
I'm sure I'll find you
Mezametara soba ni iru yo
When I wake up, I'll stay beside you
ashita mo
tomorrow as well
Preview
Listen, work is work,
おまえさ　仕事は仕事なんだから
so you can't pull this moody,
pouty nonsense, all right?
ふてくされたり
すねたりしてちゃダメだろ
You've accepted the job,
now do it right. Got it?
受けた以上はさ　ちゃんとやれよ
分かったか？
Here we go.
いくぞ
Next time on Sankarea,
episode 11:
"Nothing... Really... Special"
If you're not going to
do it right, then step down!
おまえ　やる気ないなら降りろよ！
Now say "everybody watch mero"!
みんな　見るメロって言えよ！